accountingcoach.com 2010-12-23

# Privacy Policy | AccountingCoach.com

Effective: February 1, 2010

### **Our commitment to privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

AccountingCoach, LLC is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the website www.accountingcoach.com. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Harold Averkamp by using our **email contact form**.

If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should **[contact TRUSTe](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=)**. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. AccountingCoach, LLC does not share, rent, trade or sell your personal information other than as described within this privacy policy. 

### **The information we collect**

The following notice (items 1-7) applies to all information collected or submitted on the AccountingCoach.com website.

  1. **Signing up for our email newsletter**  
On some pages you can sign up to receive our free email newsletter. We collect your first name and email address only. We use this information only when sending you our latest newsletter messages. We will never provide your personal information to any third party and promise to only send relevant information pertaining to our website AccountingCoach.com.

We follow all rules and regulations put forth in the ******[CAN-SPAM Act](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/business/ecommerce/bus61.shtm)**. You can unsubscribe yourself from our email list at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link found at the end of each and every email we send.

  2. **Purchasing one of our products**  
We use **[PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=xpt/general/Privacy-outside)** and **[Google Checkout](https://checkout.google.com/)** to process all payments made online. These are two of the safest ways to send payments online. Most importantly, it allows you as the consumer the comfort of knowing none of your credit card information will be shared with us.

PayPal and Google both share a limited amount of your information with us such as your name, email address, and sometimes home address for the sole purpose of properly delivering the product you ordered. None of this personal information will be used for any purpose other than delivering the product you ordered and notifying you when important updates become available.

  3. **Registering to participate in our online forum**  
We collect the username and email address you provide when registering to use our online forum. We do not use this information for any purpose; however, we at this community reserve the right to reveal your identity (or whatever information we know about you) in the event of a complaint or legal action arising from any message posted by you. We log all internet protocol addresses accessing this website. You can read more about our **Terms of Service**.

  4. **Tracking and statistics**  
We use only non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. 

  5. **Google AdSense and cookies**  
We use Google AdSense to supply our visitors with relevant advertisements throughout our website. Google uses cookies in order to make these ads more relevant to our visitors. **[Learn more about cookies and how to opt-out of them](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)**.

  6. **Applying for a job**  
If you wish to display a job post on our site you will be taken to a third-party service provider's site in order to Post Job, Preview Job, Enter your Payment, and Complete the posting of the job. Although the page displays accountingcoach.com at the top, the information collected on this page is governed by the privacy policy of our third-party service provider. They will then share back the information with us in order for us to post the job lisitng on our site.

  7. **Affiliate program**  
If you wish to join our affiliate program you will be directed to a third-party site in order to complete your registration. The information collected is governed by our third-party service provider's privacy policy. Your information is then shared back with AccountingCoach.com for the purpose of fulfilling your request to become our affiliate.

### **Legal disclaimer**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

### **Forum**

If you use the forum or blog on this website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

### **Tell-a-friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. AccountingCoach stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

### **Customer testimonials**

We post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information. Prior to posting a customer's testimonial we do obtain the customer's consent to post their name along with their testimonial.

### **Security**

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can email us by using our ******email contact form**.

### **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. Cookies can be either session cookies or persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when you close your browser and is used to make it easier for you to navigate our website. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You may delete or decline cookies by changing your browser settings. (Click "Help" in the toolbar of most browsers for instructions.)

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited.

### **Third-party cookies**

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, or service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, or service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart. 

### **Clear gifs (web beacons/web bugs)**

Our third-party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. web beacons/web bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

### **Updating or correcting personally identifiable information**

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it by making the change within your account page or by emailing our Customer Support by using our ******contact form**.

### **Our commitment to privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

### **How to contact us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please contact us by using our ******email contact form** or the following postal address.

> _AccountingCoach, LLC  
>  1109 W. Blackhawk Dr.  
>  Fort Atkinson, WI 53538  
>  United States_

### **Changes in this privacy statement**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
